MATTHEW MARTIN

Herndon, VA 20171 ♦ 571-247-6010 ♦ matthewdeanmartin@gmail.com https://github.com/matthewdeanmartin

I'm an experienced and effective technical lead. More than anything I enjoy working with software developers and writing code.

I have been involved in AI since before it was called AI. In graduate school, it was mathematical modeling and forecasting. At Burston Marsteller, I wrote scikit learn machine learning models to analyse social media data. Since the LLM revolution, I have published several working side projects on github exploring the use and application of LLMs.

See long resume for full details of 24 years of experience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tech Lead (Supervisor), Artemis Consulting, for US Copyright Office 2019-2024

- Led technical team (10-15 people) to deliver the Public Record copyright search engine to production, starting from a greenfield application. My team integrated with 5-6 other similar sized teams, each developing related applications.
- Supervisor for 3-5 subordinates, mostly software developers, but also QA/BA/Scrum Master roles. Conducted technical interviews, wrote tickets, set quality standards, filled skill gaps, retained core dev team for five years.
- Wrote *significant* amounts of code in Python, TypeScript, Gitlab build scripts, Terraform code in all areas of the application. Code reviewed code of other developers. Used tooling to find & fix even more code issues
- Maintained good relationships with client. Participated and complied with all areas of Agile, Scrum and SAFe software methodology.
- Using high level guidance from the architect, filled in the details of a cloud native application that balanced complexity, costs and elegance. Shipped application on time because complexity and scope were aggressively managed.
- To ensure scalability, added rate limiting, REDIS caching, SQS queuing and Lambda Serverless to search engine to ensure that search engine could handle peak load.
- Collaborated and supervised UX Specialist and supervised front end developer and accessibility specialists. Applied templates and design system. Campaigned and succeeded in convincing organization to manage the shared UI component library as a formal project, which reduced project risk for all teams.

Systems Architect, ASRC, supporting USPTO 2019-2019

- Participate in various proof of concepts for docker, kiosks, RPA, Azure Chatbots. All projects done in the context of the USPTO Architecture Office in their effort to spread new architectural patterns in the organization.
- Applied 3rd party UI templates to create beautiful demos.

Software Developer (Supervisor), Burson Marsteller, 2016-2019

- Supervisor for 2-5 software developers.
- Maintenance development on legacy marketing and public relations analytics apps.
- Continuously tuned ec2 autoscaling to support a variable load
- Transformed architecture of AWS app to reduce bill to save, ballpark, \$100k a year

Senior Software Engineer, Forsmarsh, supporting NIST, VA 2014-2016

- Wrote REST based microservice with OOP middle tier, C# .NET and Python
- Applied UX team's UI templates and VA design system to create beautiful UI

Software Developer, CACI, supporting DoD/Pentagon 2012-2014

MATTHEW MARTIN Page 2

• Microsoft shop with Oracle database. Maintenance development on C# .NET webapp. ASP.NET services with OOP design.

Senior Consultant, Procentrix, supporting TSA 2008-2012

• Maintenance developer for a C# .NET ASP.NET and MS SQL Server application

DBA/Software Developer III, DRC, supporting USAF and NARA 2005-2008

• MS SQL Server DBA tasks as well as application development tasks in C#, asp, ASP.NET. UI work done with server-side rendering.

Systems Developer I, Prince William County, 1998-2005

SKILLS

- Excellent: Python, .NET, C#, TypeScript, Javascript. Good enough: Java. Legacy: VB6, VBA, VB.NET. Willing and eager to learn: Rust, Go, PHP, Ruby
- Ops: SQL Server, Postgres, REDIS, Opensearch, Bash, Terraform, Docker
- Cloud: AWS EC2, ECS, ECR, RDS, API Gateway, ALB, DynamoDB, SQS
- More keywords in long resume. Willing and eager to learn more about Azure.

EDUCATION

Masters of Economics, University of Akron, Ohio, 1996-1998 BSBA Finance, University of Akron, Ohio, 1990-1996